# MOSES MHLWANA

mosesmhlwana@gmail.com | +27 66 395 4880

## **Personal Information**

First Name : Moses.

Last Name : Mhlwana.

Date of Birth : 01/01/1999.

Nationality : South African.

**Gender** : Male.

spoken Languages:English, IsiXhosa, Sepedi, Isizulu.,Email Address:mosesmhlwana@gmail.com

**Phone number** : +27 66 395 4880

Physical Address : 26 Johannes Manyabile str

Pretoria, Saulsville

0125

#### Profile:

Innovative, task-driven and passionate Systems developer with a variety of skills, knowledge and experience, Equipped with software development skills, IOT, and automation. Providing IT & IOT expertise and advice in the design, creation, development, testing, implementation documentation of new and enhanced applications and systems, in accordance with the agreed framework of programming standards. I always produce logical and technical specifications, I write code, compile, test and implement applications in compliance with system development life cycle(SDLC). I have great interpersonal and leadership skills, work well in teams/groups and also just by myself.

### **Education**

### **Tshwane University of Technology**

Feb 2018 - Apr 2022

### N.Diploma in IT(Intelligent Industrial Systems/Computer Systems)

• Focus Area: Software Development, IOT, Technical Support, and Automation.

### **Extra-curricular Activities**

#### · GKSS Chairperson:

Jan 2019 - july 2021

As the Geekulcha Student Society chairperson, my role with the team was to find ways we could bridge the gap between industries and ICT students, and then find a way to execute the ideas as a team. We managed to connect the students on campus with a variety of companies like Squidnet, Geekulcha, The Business Clinic, AWS, RedBull(redbull basement) and organizations.

### · Google Developer Student Club TUT chairperson:

June 2019 - June 2020

Google Developers program for university students, designed to help students build their mobile and web development skills and knowledge. It is open to any student, ranging from novice developers who are just starting, to advanced developers who want to further their skills.

#### · Lab assistant:

June 2019 - july 2021

My role was to help students with their projects and help them with chapters they need clarification

### **Skills**

Programming Languages: C++, C, Java, php, JavaScript, PLC, Assembly, C#, HTML & CSS, SQL..

Technologies & FrameWorks: Laravel, Node.JS, Raspberry-pi, Node-Red, Embarcadero, MySQL, Postgresql, Azure cloud, Git, Nginx, firebase, Arduino, MSO.

Soft Skills: Interpersonal skills, Teamwork, leadership skills.

# **Professional Experience**

#### Geekulcha

Gauteng, Pretoria

Systems Engineer - Enterprise Systems, Network, Digital Learning, IoT solutions, Security, & DPC.

Oct 2020 - Jan 2023

- Built office servers on a Raspberry-pi.
- Built an Enterprise office temperature and humidity monitoring system, integrated with a waiting room assistant screen.
- Built a reimbursement and grocery system for enterprise.
- Built an Enterprise working portal, that allows all enterprise communications, and files sharing to be all done on the platform.
- •Built a check-in and registration system for a government event(CPSI awards 2022).
- ·built a smart egg incubator.
- ·Built an irrigation system prototype...
- Hosted, Mentored, and facilitated Hackathons organized by the company.
- Mentored and lectured on Vacworks, a program by the company, with an objective to educate and engage high school students on the 4th IR technologies and how it can be used to start business.

## **Department of Home Affairs**

Gauteng, Pretoria

Indexer- Digitalization indexer

Jan 2023 - Present

• Responsible for the digitalization of home affairs records.

## Features and links

LinkedIn

Geekulcha article profile

Department of water and sanitation

Times Live article about my system prototype

Expresso NEWS.

## References

Mixo Ngoveni: Geekulcha CEO mixo@geekulcha.com | 0743730639

**Trudie Pullen: supervisor at Home Affairs** 

trudie.pullen@dha.gov.za | 0725276947

Tiyani Nghonyama : Geekulcha COO

tiyani@geekulcha.com

Jacob Masingi: Vulingqondo digital labs CEO jacobmasingi@vulinqondodl.com | 0682552462

# **EXPERIENCE SUMMARY & ITEMISED COMPUTER KNOWLEDGE**

LEVEL	DESCRIPTION
1	Had appropriate training only
2	Limited practical experience
3	Solid, practical experience
4	Well versed, extensive experience
5	Expert, extensive experience

EXPERIENCE	LEVEL	YEARS	PERIOD	COMMENTS			
(e.g. Developer, Business Analyst, Project M			Liniop	JOINIAL LITTO			
Systems Developer	5	2020-2023	3	My role was to build			
cyclee zevelepe.				and maintain enterprise			
				systems, both software			
				applications and			
				electronic systems			
Digital Indexer	5	2023-		My role is to digitize			
G		Current		Home Affairs Records.			
LANGUAGES	LEVEL	YEARS	LAST USED	COMMENTS			
(e.g. C++, C#, Java, etc.)							
C++	5	2018-2023	2023	used it to for developing			
				electronic systems and			
				desktop Applications			
Php	5	2021-2023	2023	Used it for developing			
				applications in Lar avel			
JavaScript	5	2021-2022	2023	Used it it for developing			
				dynamic content for web			
				applications			
PLC	5	2019-2023	2023	Used it for heavy			
				current electronic			
				systems			
Java	5	2020-2022	2023	Used it it for developing			
				applications			
С	5	2014-2023	2023	Used it for low current electronic systems			
Assembly	3	2019-2020	2022	Used it it for developing			
•				PIC electronic systems			
DEVELOPMENT METHODOLOGIES	LEVEL	YEARS	LAST USED	COMMENTS			
(e.g. Agile, Scrum, etc.)							
Node js	5	2018-2023	2023				
Vue.js	5	2019-2023	2023				
Laravel framework	5	2020-2023	2023	Used it it for developing			
				applications			
Arduino	5	2014-2023	2023	Used it for building			
				electronic systems.			
Node red	5	2016-2023	2023	Used it for wiring			
				electronic systems.			
Cisco Packet tracer	4	2018-2021	2023	Used it for developing			
Oldoo I dokot tracci	]	2010-2021	2020	network simulations			
Raspberry Pi	5	2018-2023	2023	Used it for building			
Taopoony i i		2010-2023	2020	electronic systems and			
				for server hosting			
SEO	4	2023	2023	101 borror hobbing			
APPLICATIONS	LEVEL	YEARS	LAST USED	COMMENTS			
(e.g. Firewall, IIS, Novell, Apache)		ILANO	LAGI GOLD	JOHN/ILITI			
Git	5	2017-2023	2023	1			
Visual Studio/ VS code	5	2018-2023	2023				
visuai Studio/ vo code	I J	2010-2023	2020				

Bootsraps	5	2017-2023	2023	
wordpress	5	2018-2021	2022	
firebase	4	2018-2022	2023	
Apache	4	2020-2023	2023	
Flutter	4	2022-2023	2023	
mysql	5	2018-2023	2023	
Nginx	5	2021-2023	2023	
Git	5	2015-2023	2023	
Node js	5	2014-2023	2023	
Tailwind	5	2021-2023	2023	